spain-holiday.com 2019-12-17

# Privacy policy of Spain-holiday.com

[www.spain-holiday.com](https://www.spain-holiday.com/) (hereafter referred to as “ **This Site** ”) is part of Spain holiday Online Rentals S.L. (hereafter referred to as “ **Spain-Holiday** ”) which is a Spanish legal registered company, registered in the Registro Mercantil de Malaga, Tomo 4211, Libro 3121, Folio 26, Sección 8, Hoja MA88747, I/A in Spain. Company registration number is: ES-B92802479.

Spain-Holiday handles personal information from users of This Site with respect and confidentiality and according to the law – and takes all reasonable steps to ensure that personal information is stored securely and accurately. Please contact us if you have any questions or comments about our policy, or our use of personal information.

This document contains detailed information about cookies and how personal data are processed. This privacy policy may be revised from time to time as we add new services, or in response to legal changes or commercial developments. Privacy policy changes will be posted on This Site.

#### **Personal information used by Spain-Holiday**

When registering, sending an enquiry or booking a holiday home through This Site, personal information such as name, phone number and email address will be saved in our database because Spain-Holiday needs to communicate important information such as booking confirmation, payment reminders and other booking related information.

When visiting or browsing This Site certain information, such as your IP address, which browser it´s being used, and information about the computer’s operating system, application version, language settings and pages that have been shown to users may be collected.

#### **Personal information use**

Personal information stored by Spain-Holiday will be used for the adequate function of This Site and the service provided, which includes, among others, the following purposes: bookings, enquiries, account administration, marketing activities, payments, sending communications, fraud detection and prevention, analytical purposes.

#### **Personal data protection**

Spain-Holiday employs strict security measures to safeguard personal information and prevent disclosure to third parties without the user’s permission. For this purpose the data storage devices are kept in a secure facility with restricted physical access – and firewalls and other measures are used to restrict electronic access. Access to personally identifiable information is only given to internal staff of Spain-Holiday requiring the information to perform a specific job. Spain-Holiday will keep the user's data safe thus cooperation with our security checks may be necessary before disclosing any information. Information will be retained for a reasonable period, or as long as legally required. To this extent, payments made through Spain-Holiday are done via a third party secure certified payment provider and Spain-Holiday does not store the full credit card details and is not liable for errors or losses on payments or money transfers.

As part of This Site, Spain-Holiday provides an internal account called Secure Inbox that allows the direct written communication between the Guest and the Owner. For security purposes, Spain-Holiday has an automated system that screens all communications for malicious or fraudulent content. That includes spam and the limitation of certain file types. Any sensitive information such as full credit card numbers that can be used for fraud may be masked automatically to ensure the safety of both Owners and Guests. Spain-Holiday may also mask contact information which can be used to establish contact outside the Secure Inbox. In case of detecting a communication with malicious content, it may be blocked entirely. All communications sent and received using the Secure Inbox will be stored by Spain-Holiday. To the extent permitted by law, Spain-Holiday will only access internal communications between Owners and Guests if required by law, if strictly necessary for security or law enforcement purposes, or if Spain-Holiday otherwise has a legitimate interest, such as to detect and prevent fraud and misuse. No communications will ever be passed on to a third party except if required by the law. Spain-Holiday may analyse anonymized content of communications to improve its services.

The personal data provided for the registration of the account as well as any other that could be provided during the booking procedure are included in a database called _Spainholiday_ duly registered with the Spanish Data Protection Agency, owned and processed by Spain holiday online rentals SL. The acceptance of these terms and conditions implies the express consent to the referred data processing. 

For the exercise of the legal rights to access, rectification, cancellation or opposition to the data treatment a written request by the data subject should be sent to the customer service department on following email [support@spain-holiday.com ](mailto:support@spain-holiday.com). You can also exercise this right by sending a letter via ordinary post to the following address: Paseo de Cerrado de Calderón, 13, Local 41, 29018 Málaga.

In case that in the compliance of the commercial relationship, third parties personal data would be communicated to Spain Holiday Online Rentals, S.L. the user guarantees that he is authorised to communicate such data and that he has provided to the data subject with the relevant information related to his communication in compliance with the legal provisions in force. Should this not be the case the user will be responsible for any infringement or penalty that could be granted to the Spain-Holiday and could indemnify and keep it harmless in this respect. 

#### **Responsible for the treatment of data**

In accordance with provisions outlined by EU Regulation (2016/679) from the European Parliament and from the Council (27th of April 2016), concerning the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and the free movement of this data as well as any other applicable regulations on data protection (hereinafter GDPR). We inform you that all personal data provided by users through the domain www.spain-holiday.com and its subdomains are treated under the responsibility of Spain Holiday Online Rentals (hereinafter, Spain-Holiday), CIF B92802479 at registered office in Paseo de Cerrado de Calderón, 13, Local 41, 29018 Malaga (Spain), telephone: + 34 951 234 435, email:support@spain-holiday.com as the owner and legal representative of the Website. 

#### **Purpose of data processing**

The personal data provided by users through the website are only used in accordance with the purpose for which the data has been collected.

\- User account: The legal basis for the processing of this data is for the execution and provision of the corresponding services: Ad management and registration of your data to facilitate management and contact with the user. This data is kept for the duration of the commercial relationship and for the time that is necessary to comply with any legal obligation.

\- Contact form: Response to communications initiated by an interested party. The treatment of this data is legitimised by the consent from the interested party. In this case, the data is kept according to the purpose for which it has been collected for, and for a maximum of 2 years, unless the party concerned withdraws their consent before this.

\- Subscription to our newsletter: Sending advertising about our products and services; information about promotions, distribution of activities and events organised by Spain-Holiday. The treatment of this data is legitimised by the consent of the interested party. This data will be kept as long as the interested party does not request the cessation of activity.

\- Sending of request: Sending and managing reservation requests to the owners or managers from the holiday homes advertised on Spain-Holiday. The legal basis for this data collection is that it is required for the initial communication, necessary for future rental contracts or pre-contractual measures carried out by the interested party. This data is kept for as long as the commercial relationship continues and during the years necessary to comply with any legal obligations.

\- Subscription to our promotion "Win a Gift Check": Sending information of our promotions, distribution of activities and events organised by Spain-Holiday.com. This data treatment is legitimised by the consent of the interested party and the data will be kept as long as the party interested does not request the cessation of the activity. 

#### **Recipients**

No personal data will be transferred to third parties.

Depending on the purpose in question, any personal data collected is categorised as a form of personal identification. This data can be in the form of your name, surname, nationality, identity document number or passport, as well as personal characteristics such as - date of birth, sex, contact information, telephone number, postal address and email address. Furthermore, this data can also relate to tourist properties - cadastral reference, address, tourist license number, and economic-banking data; all of this data will be treated with strict confidentiality, applying technical and organisational security measures, required by the current data protection regulations. Spain-Holiday will not communicate this personal data to third parties, unless it is required to do so for legal or jurisdictional purposes or if the communication of this data is necessary in relation to the purpose of the treatment itself.

#### **Rights of the person in which the personal data belongs to**

In regards to the treatment of personal data, the owner of this data can exercise their rights to access, rectify, request deletion, oppose, limit, or withdraw consent, among others options provided under the regulations of GDPR. This can be done by sending an email to the following address, support@spain-holiday.com, or by writing to Spain-Holiday and attaching a photocopy of a valid ID document along with what you request regarding the treatment of your personal data. If you do not agree with the treatment of your personal data, you can file a claim with the Spanish Agency for Data Protection AEPD (www.aepd.es).

#### **Modification of the Privacy Policy and Treatment of Personal Data**

Spain-Holiday reserves the right to modify and/or update the content of this privacy policy and the processing of personal data at any time, either partially or in its entirety. Therefore, the user is advised to read the cookie policy carefully every time they access the website or periodically in order to be fully informed on the latest and most updated version of these policies. 

#### **Changes to company status**

 **

Spain-Holiday reserves the right to disclose the collected information to any new Owner for the event of entering into an ownership agreement with another business. Spain-Holiday will not otherwise disclose, sell, or distribute the information to any third party without permission – unless required to do so by law.

#### **Use of Cookies**

Spain-Holiday uses cookies to allow the users of This Site to be recognized across pages, and also allow the choices of the user to be remembered. Cookies are used as well to simplify the signing-in procedure, keep track of monitor usage.

#### **Types of used cookies**

Spain-Holiday uses the following types of cookies:

  * Technical cookies: These are strictly necessary cookies for an adequate function of This Site.

  * Performance cookies: These cookies collect information about how visitors use This Site. These cookies do not collect information that can identify a user of This Site. All information these cookies collect is anonymous and is only used to improve the performance of This Site. Spain-Holiday uses these cookies: to remember the visitor searches and accommodation viewed, to get statistics about how visitors use This Site, e.g. the number of visitors to a page, identify any errors that occur so that we improve This Site.
  * Functionality cookies: These cookies allow This Site to remember the choices visitors make, such as the visitor´s username in order to provide enhanced and personalized features.

Spain-Holiday uses the following owned and third-party cookies:

ASP.NET_SessionId, .AspNet.TwoFactorRememberBrowser |  Security |  Used to maintain an anonymised user session by the server. |  Spain-Holiday.com  
---|---|---|---  
SHAdminLoginCookie, SHApplicationCookie |  Authentication |  Used for our login system so the user does not have log login every time. |  Spain-Holiday.com  
SHC_AdWords_AccountCampaign |  Advertising |  Used for collect information regarding our campaigns. |  Spain-Holiday.com  
__qca |  Advertising |  They provide website rankings, and the data they collect is also used for audience segmentation and advertising. |  Quantcast  
__ssid |  Site features |  Ensures that Google can collect user information for Google Maps and videos hosted by YouTube. |  Google  
__stripe_mid, __stripe_sid |  Security/Authentication |  Generated session cookie for recognising a user. |  Stripe  
__utma, __utmc, __utmv, __utmz, _ga |  Analytics |  Used for Google Analytics. |  Google  
cookiePolicyAccepted |  Site features |  Used to check if the user accepted our cookie policy. |  Spain-Holiday.com  
currentLanguage |  Site features |  Used to keep track of the current language selected on our page. |  Spain-Holiday.com  
firstPageSeen |  Site features |  Used to get the first page visited. |  Spain-Holiday.com  
intercom-* |  Site features / Support |  Used for our live support chat to remember the user and the conversations. |  Intercom  
newsletterPopShownThisVisit |  Site features |  Used to not show the newsletter popup if the user has already seen it. |  Spain-Holiday.com  
shortlistId |  Site features |  Used to save our short list (List of Holiday homes the user has marked as interesting) |  Spain-Holiday.com  
tms_VisitorID |  Fresh Relevance |  Stores a unique id for the device. This is used to keep track of your shopping, to send/show you offers that relate to the products viewed, so you can be contacted by email if you seem to be having problems, or to help us improve the Website. |  Spain-Holiday.com  
  
#### **Access to cookie data by third parties**

Only Spain-Holiday has access to Spain-Holiday cookies.

#### **Length of time the cookies used remain active**

The cookies used by Spain-Holiday may have different lifespans. The maximum lifespan is 60 days from the last user´s visit to the website. Nevertheless cookies can be deleted from the browser at any moment by the link provided in the next section.

#### **Removal of cookies**

#### **Instructions For Managing Cookies Internet Explorer 7, 8, and 9**

Click on the Tools menu, and then select Internet Options.

Click on the Privacy tab. Move the slider to choose your preferred settings. For more specialised cookie settings, click on Sites or Advanced. For instructions on deleting cookies in Internet Explorer, click [here](https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/278835/how-to-delete-cookie-files-in-internet-explorer)

#### **Google Chrome**

Click on the Chrome menu, and then select Settings.

Click Show advanced settings. Click on Content settings to choose your preferred settings. For instructions on deleting cookies in Chrome, click [here](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en-GB&hlrm=en&topic=14666&ctx=topic). 

#### **Mozilla Firefox**

Click on the Firefox button (or Tools menu), and then select Options. For Mac OS X users, click on the Firefox menu, and then select Preferences.

Click on the Privacy panel to choose your preferred settings. For more specialised cookie settings, set Firefox will: to Use custom settings for history. For instructions on deleting cookies in Firefox, click [here](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored). 

#### **Safari 5.1 and later**

Click on the Safari menu, and then select Preferences.

Click on the Privacy tab to display cookie settings. Choose your preferred settings. For more specialised cookie settings, click on Details. For instructions on deleting cookies in Safari, click [here](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH5049?locale=es_ES). **
